Daniel A. Pinedo

Strategic Human Resources

1 213.999.5619

@ daniel.pinedo@cgu.edu

% pinedo.org

SUMMARY

Daniel has over a decade of experience in consulting, management, university teaching, and IT roles. His primary expertise is in forming, leading, and developing cross-disciplinary teams of specialists and researchers in order to complete difficult and time-sensitive business and technical projects. He studies and measures how diverse, inclusive workplaces spark innovation and intrapreneurship in firms.

His vision is for the ethical implementation of industry 4.0 in relation specifically to recruitment, talent management and human capital strategy in the United States and global markets.

Daniel finds joy in facilitating growth and development in employees as a trained executive and mindfulness coach with over 15 years of practice.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Project Manager

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

10/2019 - Current

Same duties as Associate Consultant plus ownership of project timelines, milestones, and personnel time and task budgeting. Team sizes are 4-8 members per project.

• PROJECT 8: Documentation sprint for preparation of final presentation of completed and vetted global employee selection and assessment model to CHRO. Project completed at 70% time and 60% personnel budget.

Associate Consultant

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

🛗 03/2019 - Current

Same duties as Research Associate plus ownership of project deliverable content, translation of research into business case for internal clients, and engagement with primary stakeholder managers.

- Member of Recruitment and Selection committee which planned recruitment events and created internal selection infrastructure
- Member of Fairness Committee which vetted projects and ensured fairness in internal selection and promotion
- Member of Strategy Committee which managed organizational effectiveness, performance management, and employee development
- PROJECT 4: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into secondary implementation stage with global alignment teams
- PROJECT 5: SME and individual interviewer for values-based assessment prototype
- PROJECT 6: SME and focus group interviewer for selection assessment design prototype
- PROJECT 7: SME and consultant for leadership model synthesis and design

Research Associate

Accenture PLC, CGU Talent Innovation Lab

11/2018 - Promotion

Organizational behavior & evaluation research specialist for Global HR / Recruitment Transformation.

- PROJECT 1: Literature review for behavioral interview theory
- PROJECT 2: SME for behavioral interview theory; initiated implementation plan with global management team
- PROJECT 3: Validated scoring measure for behavioral interview into pilot stage with global alignment teams

Statistical Consultant

Lisa Kaczmarczyk PhD Consulting, LLC

12/2019 12/2019

% http://www.lisakaczmarczyk.com/

Social Network Analysis with R programming language for client program evaluation spanning multiple universities.

• completion of a social network analysis of a cross-section of three attitudinal constructs across three universities including actor-event network graphs, interpretation consultation, and commented Rmarkdown script.

RECENT EXPERIENCE

Management Consultant

Arup

% https://www.arup.com

Organizational effectiveness evaluation plan consultation team member for Los Angeles office HR department

- Completed developmental and formative evaluation plan for new-hire onboarding program across IT, HR, Facilities, and Finance Departments
- Provided recommendations to senior HR managers for program improvement and monitoring for turnover reduction, improved communication across departments, and productivity due to potential increase in employee engagement.

Executive Coach

Getty Leadership Institute, LeAD Labs

1 05/2019 - 08/2019

% https://gli.cgu.edu/

Primary support for three senior international museum executives during leadership training and assessment center program.

- Assisted clients in creation of development plan based on assessment center, 360°, and StrengthsFinder results
- Follow-up with each client 6-8 weeks following leadership program related to completion of specific SMART goals and creation of longterm professional development goals

Management Consultant

Undisclosed Property Management Firm

1 03/2019 - 06/2019

Organizational culture project for private, family-owned property management firm currently undergoing succession-related change with a portfolio of over \$1 billion in residential and commercial real-estate assets.

- Diagnosed internal-facing stress related to values signaling from family management through executive management
- Provided business case for implementing values communications strategies with potential for increased organizational commitment and overall firm performance
- Connected business strategy with identified cultural values for implementation in management training program

Team Lead

BCG Gamma Datathon

Invite-only case competition for BCG data analytics group among graduate students from USC Marshall, UCLA Anderson, and CGU Drucker management schools.

- Recruited ad-hoc cross-functional team of experts in the fields of artificial intelligence, financial engineering, data science, management, and organizational behavior
- Provided case formulation training, strategy, and high-level architecture for technical solution

Management Consultant

ICM Partners

1 09/2018 - 01/2019

% icmpartners.com

Organizational behavior project for Top 5 creative talent agency undergoing HR restructuring.

• 1-year development plan presented to CHRO with training cost savings projected to be \$10-\$15,000 per new hire

Lecturer

Mount Saint Mary's University

% msmu.edu

Undergraduate faculty in psychology department developing and teaching courses in Research Methods, Social Psychology, Positive Psychology, and Organizational Psychology.

- Managed increase in participation in undergraduate research colloquium of students by 300% and outside attendees by over 1000%
- Academic counseling for 15 students per semester that included tracking graduation requirements, course selection, career counseling, monitoring degree progress, and crisis counseling with 100% graduation rate

Interim Director / Manager

Sofia University Electroencephalography Lab

Academic EEG lab studying brainwave correlates of meditative states of consciousness.

- Raised private external grant pledges of \$500,000+
- Created training program for graduate students with four paid positions for training in running experiments with human subjects

EDUCATION

MA Psychology in Organizational Behavior & Evaluation

Claremont Graduate University

• Emphasis in Management

GPA
3.7 / 4.0

MA Clinical Psychology

Sofia University

Palo Alto, CA

BA

Naropa University

♀ Boulder, CO

COURSEWORK HIGHLIGHTS

MBA

Accounting Corporate Finance Economics of Strategy Macroeconomics

Organizational Behavior

Organizational Behavior Organizational Culture Organizational Theory

Statistics

ANOVA Multiple Regression Social Network Analysis Psychometric Network Analysis

Categorical Data Analysis Non-Parametric Data Analysis Factor Analysis

Structural Equation Modeling

Programming

R C++ Java